I...a thumbs up.
Okay, is three thirty we're going to go and welcome, welcome everybody to
add packaging...deployment for the windows universal platform my
name's barclay hill I'm the program manager lead for app platform
...specifically the deployment area and with me is jason?
The jason actually owns core deployment on my...so,
our team is actually responsible for basically all the
verbs with apps so if you're installing and...from the store.
Running...assign installing and app through our enterprise kind of scenarios
mgm basically all verbs related to an app packaging at
working with the under visual studio those types of scenarios that's all our team.
I'm supposed to remind everybody to please fill out
a valuation and please do we have a friendly competition going within the
app model or were fairly competitive so, tell us what...tell us what
she didn't like what you're hoping we're talking about and, we'd like to see the feedback so,
this is a...model map of the sessions than ads at
...presented here at the build
conference as well as one session coming up at the ignite conference
...here they call a store because
that's store apps right but, basically we're going to be talking about packaging
and deployment fundamentals and specifically what's new in windows ten.
As you can see is that somy boss
...clinic who presented kind of the lap around
...he present on the first day I would I would actually suggest you
...a look at that was a good high-level overview of everything that's new
that's coming from the app model what's left still in the week is
app services and shell integration which is friday please take a look at that.
So, specifically...we're going to be covering today
is benefit benefits of universal windows app packages
and deployment specifically diving deep into kind of the packaging
and deployment from...perspective looking at what it looks like locally and,
kind of reviewing what's new with windows to in that respect we're also going to cover
app storage improvements getting more app with let space and the
continue support for...down level packages or previous
platform version packages and then at the end I'll wrap it up
before we get dive into this how many how many folks in the audience attended
...session last year anybody couple,
couple how many folks have an app in the store or
build the modern out...while fair amount and for phone?
And, for desktop.
...pretty good pretty good mix okay all right so at
this structure I'll turn it over to the...the cover the benefit.
Thanks barclay so like barclay mention my name is jason salami
imc program manager on the windows what
recalling app model core deployment team so,
I own the verbs install update remove
etc if you...sander clinics talk on wednesday you mention kind of this
cradle to grave model and he had install update and remove there so those are the kind of three that
...so the things that we wanted to talk about today here was basically
kind of taking a step back and really looking at the benefits of why should you go and build
universal windows app and what we've done is we basically broken down into three pillars in
the very the most important thing is that these things are still
topics packages that, you know, we introduces...windows...we've improved on
...eight-point one and here we are again continuing to improve on the story so we broken down the
story...three basic pillars the first one is all about easy deployment again you heard
...talk about this yesterday but ...you're installing when thirty-two apps from the old
in days...roughed install they take some time you get a click-through all these dialogues you have to build
the install yourself you have to build the updating model you have to figure out, you know,...connection
no internet connection you have to do reboot etc it's kind of painful...really,
really I'd say fragile story and the worst part about is when the app is removed often
times a lot of...is left over...the system and this causes the pc to slow down
it causes problems over the life of kind of the device so with app...and kind of
what these universal windows apps we really provide a clean way
that safe to install these packages seamless updates no reboot
...so the next kind of pillar that we wanted to talk about is the
declarations story kind of the way that we
expressed to the system what the package or the app is intending to do
...had done via the...so barclay will do a little bit of a deep dive
...a bit later but the manifest provides the package
in the system of the powerful way of kind of expressing what it wants to due to the system
example extensions registrations etc we have the formal versioning model that tells us how we
...and then we finally another good point is being able to target particular
device families again barkley we'll talk about the more little bit later and the last one which I'm really,
really psyched about is basically all the space savings that you get when you have these types of apps...breaks
down into three buckets and going to talk about these in more depth right now the first one
is incremental updates which is basically moving from vone vtwo the
space savings that you get if there's things that haven't changed from the old version to the new version
the...is file single-engine saying
...it's very similar concept but across packages that come from the windows store
had the same kind of origin and the last one is about partial resource downloads and
these are for all...developers that have multilingual or apps that are
targeting like these very large-scale devices or small-scale...all scale devices we
...make sure that, you know, the windows phone device isn't having to download
drum resources for like say the xbox of the pc or etc...diving a
little bit deeper for incremental updates the way this works is actually pretty simple we have kind
of a to phase model and the first phase let's say we're going to update to
app version to the first optimization that we provide these apps is basically a
file level optimization if there's a file that hasn't changed between version
...version to there's no reason to go downloaded again...actually no reason to go and, you know, use that
bandwidth...that time so we do is we end up creating a shared version of
that file that can be used between those two obviously the old version will eventually be removed
but until it's removed the file is basically shared between those two the second type of
optimization that we provide is on a block level so we have a piece of
metadata that lives in the package called...block map you can go and crack open
...package and see it basically
has sixty-four kilobyte compressed representations in hash of the file
itself and what that allows us to do...allows us to uniquely identify blocks within
a file and if we see that hey there's blocks here that are identical between the old version
...the new version well there's also no reason to re download those again we simply
copy them over and then the files for the blocks that are not equal those get read
download from the store so it's a very clean model and you see here what ends up getting downloaded
is three blocks in this example now to...of take a step back and look at this
and the more holistic picture when we think about like on a windows phone
...desktop pc or xbox new want to go and download and updated takes so much time like I have
I've seen devices in the past where I want to download and update for a gamer say...
update is like fifty or sixty...like what's going on here why is so big and it's like, you know,
bug fixes or something in a sub notes and it's one of those things where it's like I don't understand but
it's really like this is one of the really big benefits I think we get as
far as updating on mobile so the next thing I want to talk about is
bridging that from these from the within the same app to the multiple apps?
In this case I have an example I have to windows store apps mahjong
and solitaire and for the sake of the example use these two...by microsoft but
that doesn't apply to apps within the same publisher let's say I download microsoft
margiana that's got a...platform a game and
then some files then I...go and I want to download solitaire so we notice hey solitaire has an
ad platform in the same game engine as well so instead of downloading those files again let's
actually go and create a shared copy that can be used between those two apps finally we download the rest
of the files now the next question that we always get...way what about...update what happens if
one of them changes as you'd expect and this case of the game engine changed.
We would re download the game engine for the new file hopefully it doesn't happen but
...file with no longer be shared between those two so we preserve everything
and the best part is...it's totally free it's like you don't have to do any extra work
...no extra coding you...to do any checks or anything the practices that we have
...places basically say if
you're using a third-party binary or library component that's,
you know, a common one just don't recompile don't change it if you have multiple apps
in the store and you have a shared library make sure its updated in the same one across all of them
and you'll be able to read those benefits as well which is great the last optimization that I want
to talk about is partial resource downloads we've heard a lot in
the keynote is that we want have these universal windows...scale from,
you know, small screens to big-screen everything in the middle and sometimes even like hollow
...no screen at all so we're starting to see a reason to have like a lot of scales or
lot-of languages if you have
a multilingual app one of the things that we did with universal windows apps if you have
an app that targets multiple devices when you have that app in your building
although scale assets instead of going
in downloading every single one of those assets on every single device we make sure that we acquire
only the ones that are needed for that device and the space savings that we've actually seen
is on the order of sometimes upwards of fifteen percent to twenty five percent depending on
scale assets obviously this is a game and there's a direct decks asset we're talking many
gigabytes especially for these larger apps that are going to start coming down pretty soon.
So, to recap the benefits of universal it's really basically three points
...these predictable and successful deployments clean install easy updates
no reboot and rot free removal...we don't have pc's being slowdown over
time and it's kind of all these benefits that we get the next one is these the declarations as part of the
...you have the ability to do a lot of things and that manifests which
...show you a bit later and, it's a very easy way to declare all that and,
xml format and basically the system understands
and is able to do all those things for you and then...on installer during a clean-up
were able to exactly...the removal of those operations and the last one
of these nowhere the bandwidth and storage savings which I just talked about so
with that I will handed over back to barclay and he's going to tell you a little bit about universal app deployment?
All right so universal windows app deployment so, we're continuing with our approach that
...the in eight-point one for phone and also...
desktop the previous versions of the package artifacts still fully supported there's
no there's no stopping any the support for anything that's actually been
published in the store for windows ten devices we'll take a look at the
manifests is exactly how this is enabled so,
essentially is that if you're working on app and have an app in the store and you want to move to
...app if it's a silverlight app on the phone we do
a full migration meaning that we go ahead and upgrade it for the user experience of
the user of the devised I don't see any different they just difference they think it's just
...simple app
update but effectively what we're actually doing as doing a migration underneath the covers
when we moved from silverlight to a universal app and pool the state that the app
...previously over to the new app any of the sterilization format...would do
in the context of your app of course you would do at launch time or you could actually implement and,
upgrade task we supported upgrade
...and this allows you to do any of that data manipulation or
...register for push notifications and whatnot so your tiles don't go dark they can
continue the to refresh what's new in windows ten
were introducing device family targeting previously
in the manifest were somewhat limited if you look at silverlight
for phone there's really just a platform version...there so it was basically
seven point eight point one and absolutely just targeted that major
minor version of the platform so there really wasn't a whole lot of
ability to take advantage of new features that would ship
in incremental update and typically the app model only...minor revving and that
could have been...sometime in-between releases now you have
the ability to actually target down...and os ...so as you can see is that
we're releasing much more frequently...releasing new features you can expect
as you could actually build updates your app to take advantage of
those specific apps are those features that we're going to introduce?
And, one area we've spent a lot of time on improving and I'll demo in a
minute is reducing the friction in the developer unlock experience.
We've gotten a lot of feedback I've gotten a lot of emails hey, why
...why when...visual studio I see this dialog, you know,
is it really been ninety-day it's,
you know, I swear the solve this last week or hey I jump on a plane
...expected to work on my app I'm walked out, you know,
it wanted me to renew my license a lot of feedback
...about that as well as feedback on mobile?
Things like well I built-in app I want to share our wealth guys on my team
...a team.
Except they don't have the tools so they have to download full visual studio and go
...device and, you know, it was working in the device locked itself back
...not sure what's going on so a fair amount of feedback actually came directly to me around
so we spent some time actually improving that and.
So, how easy is...to unlock well it's really easy will take a look
will look at it is actually in settings now you go into settings...a can server a
converge setting cl that basically can enable side load or developer
mode we'll talk about that more once we get into the demo I'm desktop...by will desktop
...mobile effectively when you're actually doing this what we're doing is we're writing some register
...back to the os
...desktop you can actually change these yourself if...and have been of course on mobile of course
it's a lot device you can't write to the registry but effectively when you're entering
...of enabling side load or developer mode
you're, you're also enabling other services to run so,
this is what it looks like...phone so it's pretty, pretty consistentwhat this looks like
on phone now the difference between side load apps and developer mode?
When you're when you don't have the developer features enabled basically all
side loading is blocked apps have to be they have to come from the store they have to be
signed by microsoft basically if you enable side loading of apps basically
your enabling app sign by authority that your device trust
...that...defined by code sign certificate the you add
to your device when you're in developer mode you're actually going a little bit step
further allowing tools to integrate with the device you're allowing the
...to deploy an app loose file deployment register
...debugged control some of the execution on the device
as well as other tools that we actually have that last option developer mode what that
actually also does it start services on the device so soon as you enable that
...you have additional services running on the device that supports the developer tooling so if
you looked at what we actually had?
eight-point one for both desktop and mobile is basically have the side
load option only and just when you...all you want to do is silo to package
...basically starting all the services whether or not you needed them or not you just one of the silo to package.
So, no, mass no fuss right
there are limitations of course desktop there is no cap on
...loaded african...unlimited side load is many apps as you want...mobile
its capsule at the twenty silo the twenty side loaded app limit.
So, what we jump into the demo?
Okay, so, when I went ahead and the I environment visual studio because I didn't want to
...the...on this I prebuilt a project has I don't want you guys
the set through the template being created the build that I'm actually running is not a
bill that was released this week ...that was released this week the developer mode
options is not fully enabled...that build but it's actually coming very soon so...open my project?
I...universal windows application project
...that familiar dialogue but it says something new instead of saying you need
...developer license it tells you go to settings and actually to
enable it and that's what I'm going to do right now I'm going to
go to settings and find under update...security.
Under for developers and there's a...so you can jump off to msdn
learn more about what these options actually do now this cp
...is or this control panel it's also can be controlled by the admin
so-if adamant for pushes down group policy to the device like in our case within microsoft
were actually enabled everybody's enabled for developer...and,
it's actually deploy that way now you can also be disabled if it is
...by the...you will not be able to turn it on here but if
you're developer and actually have admin level privileges on your
device you can enable that so for the demo as I'm going to and there's the dialogue that kind of
...you about silo ding when enable...developer...so if I
...back to the idea...just...so.
That dialog if you worked in visual studio in the
...basically was on a schedule task in
...was tied to the expiration of your developer
...or your developer license as long as you stay unlocked
you won't see this but if you do go back into a lock state because you change to yourself
...your admin changes you will see that dialogue when you actually loads or code so, when we take a look at the
manifests...the...so you guys can read it back they're
...be very familiar to what people have seen before thing every time I've demo
...wow you guys are really proud of this xml document if we actually
are...declared of deployment artifact it's really
...helps us and deployment understand what we're going
to do against the machine when we go to deploy the application this is much different than
m assign we own them aside technology as well as I of course
is imperative so it has a possibility through custom actions
and whatnot to run code when the installer is going to run so,
we do think that this is a big deal...it presents lots of benefits and it's also what helps
us to have highly reliable app installs so?
...a look at this one thing you might notice we made the decision is
that for windows universal
app starting with ten this might not always stay this way but for now we're just going
ahead and adding a phone identity element this identity element here this phone
product id is primarily was the identifier we used when we actually
had the separation of stores we have the phone store and we had the desktop store now we
have one store given that we have devices out there that will be upgraded from a to
eight one to ten the primary identifier for these apps
...already in the ecosystem is a stone ninety now when you create a
project or the project that you have for your existing app this good that you have is
just been uniquely created at the time you created the project when you submitted to the
store the store ...to see if you're spinning is a update to an existing app in the
...jacked what...real product ideas so when the when
the app update comes down we use a combination of the product id
in the package family name this identity that we actually use?
Is defined?
Here you can see it's a combination the product family
names combination of the name of the package to publisher so,
on we also have a package...full name
...includes...architecture whether or not it's a bundle in the version and that's the
strong identifier we're not dealing with upgrades but this phone product ideas
...allows us to pull these actually together to perform these upgrades the other
new feature with them mass and I'm actually going to.
Make this the.
If you've ever looked at the manifest before and,
looked at the code behind the actual designer you may have seen what we called the
...model version in the past and this is something like for windows eight-point
...six-point-three and for phone eight-point one it was six-point-three point one
and then basically match with a model version that we...independently so,
when we add features to the app model...actually rev this is
what give you the ability to actually target specific versions of the
our app model those app model versions really didn't change but
...when we did a major minor release would we actually do
anchorman unless we did a major we would actually increase
that number the major numbers you could probably be aware of it's actually more of a marketing
number of the actual building commended number...we...some digits in there but so,
that first number
...basically a branding version number the next number there is?
The minor number which is zero here it's basically defaulting to what sdk as
...n of course is the build.
Increment number and this is a revision number so what does allows you to do
ads we crank on and we're going to add features you can have apps out
and ecosystem you can actually take advantage for some of the
users I've taken those updates to take advantage of those new at model features
...runtime features this...version is
what defines applicability of the package to the os so,
essentially what happens when you click the button the store.
Lots of communication goes through the pipeline but basically the store sends us down
...string...been captured at the point of ingestion and we
actually look at that and it's a combination of this as well as a number of other factors and we define
...applicability to the os and that's what tells, you know,
windows...download pipe actually site okay go ahead and go get us the bits
this is applicable max version tested.
We'll get into too many details but this actually defines the
process space so if you could you can actually increment that up to say have
...these different versions but the max known version that them the...as of
...as aware of is why it would run it in that process space for compatibility reasons so target
device families you can see is in the name...windows dot universal and that means
any platform that supports or that's derived from the universal
out platform that supports that would actually be able to
two-run those apps f they have that version of that subsystem.
You can also define multiples
...might see also in this release of bs there is no designer on it that will come right now you
just get the xml there is intelligence because it's background...the I
can define the new one and this a name.
Windows dot.
Xbox of course I would go through them inversion so on and define it as such
and this is kind of a hunt sequence.
basically what this would mean is I think the typical scenarios you'd want to actually build
...adaptive app that would probably target all these devices you want to increase your market
potential as much as possible but you could run into cases where the platforms
...that you want specific versions of platforms right you say well
I the min level for a universal app I would support this version but
these specific devicefamilies I need this version so you can do something
that's even specific for let's say mobile.
Like this or desktop.
If I take universal off of that basically
that makes that package applicable only to that target devices family target
device family because it's not just a desktop as you can imagine it could be anything that's running
full windows core ride it's going to be two and one a tablet
...so on but for the sake of our demo I'm going-to leave it as universal.
And, remove this guy.
That's all I'm...you in the manifests basically on the new pieces as jason
...pointed out before this it's an apache, you know,
this is what this is more evolution...laying blaring new features.
I have my project my universal windows application...took a look at the manifest
...we actually take a look at building and packaging so
if you're a mobile dab or windows mobile that you might notice there's a difference
we actually move to the app axes app axes have distinct
verbs I can build and then I can package whereas for silverlight zap
...basically we put it into the same build
...so you'll build you'll f five when you
...five that is that requires that tooling integration I talked about
...nine you really need to enable developer mode not just side
load for that actually work the real difference here is that when you...five.
We're doing what we call it...file deployment and the reason why we do this is...
keep efficient we don't want to package up...the whole package over every time every time you
...five so we do a...we basically update...files
that have changed and then actually start...bagger again...so,
when you're under...five or you're in the ide and...you're actually not deploying from
package you're just doing...follow employment so anything that's related to packaging
related features like incremental download or anything that's associate with
...footprint you're not going to see that...five-time that's basically the whole...a lot of?
If I...package this thing...click I go to store
...and packages...at this dialog...you want to
...one from the store you want to build one for local right there's,
there's a couple of different additional work we do and
we're going to the store when we're going local but for the sake of our demo here I'm going to create local.
So, in this dialog you're basically going to it's going to find the output location
and it's going to want to bumped aversion so, is jason mention before we have
a formal versioning this is one thing we didn't have...
silverlight the somewhat of a problem without formal versioning and silverlight you
could just put...in their whatever it was basically the
developer defying the problem with that is that we could get into cases that and certain
silos scenarios...we could...level and application
that's typically never really what you intend to do so,
when we go to deploy we always check the version
numbers of the packages so it's going to...is going to harvard
too increment for you and if you want to generate an app bundled app
bundles what jason's mentioning before where we can have...a packages
a packages that are applicable to certain class of devices or dx levels
screen sizes so on in this dialog you can define the
architectures you're going to create now if you attended
...session last year and basically what you saw it visual studios that
artifacts were the same the manifest, you
know, the universal app the manifests was the same other than the version number...it was a kind of a
...the integrated environment...to
heads which is an enabled you to share a lot of code between desktop and
phone now...ten you can actually share binary...the same binary that's the same
app increase you can actually even create a bungled that has all the
...you want to support so you're not slapping
like five-four different packages up to the store you're just submitting one and you can version
of is one and within that are packages
...applicable to architectures so on and those have version numbers
...for the sake of the demo otherwise I'm just going to actually build...individual packages?
Okay, it's going.
Ok, so, I'll put my packages here.
So, for desktop,
desktop in...you can run...you can do lots of different things right
...the tools pretty much effectively run full trust right and,
when we produce packages we do things like we produce
a nice little script that you can actually run to deploy it?
And, of course we've already enabled dev mode...deployed my application right if you want to see it
...is here.
This got deployed.
Now for...
For mobile we don't have that model nothing runs...ross everything runs and what we call
low box so even the developer tooling we're actually integrate
...inside of a container we only allow the developer tooling
what it's allowed to actually do on the platform this prevents, you know,
somebody using tools against the device to attacker apps or as user to
attack your information and whatnot so effectively...runs and what we
call a low box so the way that you actually deploys you...to deploy through agents
in tools that actually bootstrap packages over to the device and actually will start them?
To deploy this on mobile.
I think the way I'm going to do this I'm not going to use the overhead projector I'm actually just going to.
If windows well let me.
What I have here my hand is basically a...six thirty?
...a allow it to project my screen.
Once to behave...okay let's try that again there it is.
So, basically I...to enable side loading on this because I'm not actually going to
...five the application just going to...from package so I'm going to go the same
Same control panel for developers.
And, I'm going to enable.
Nowdue to an unfortunate bugging probably why you guys are getting this feature actually need to
...developer mode for now but
was make-believe we didn't see that if you only need to silo package you just need enable
side loading now for this case about I have actually enabled.
We have a new command line tool like we've shipped previously.
The only deals...
Uw ways or universal windows applications so they all tools
app deployed command dealt web three-point-one packages and then we actually
had to deploy utility for eight packages so on but this deployment tool
basically are targeting devices that are locked it deploys agents and,
whatnot the way you actually do this is...the sdk.
...that for deployment.
...packages are here.
When I go back to the arm package because I didn't do a bundle I did
individuals and I'm just going to copy the path?
The...command prompt.
This is the arm so basically I'm...I'm
...is when app deploy.
Command.
And, the first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to give it the verb I want to install
right.
And, then I want to teller world of file is.
Which the...should be?
That guy the debug version of my arm package and then I need to give it an ip
address
...given...ip address because we're enabling a very sought-after feature
...enabling remote deployment I'm not able to demo it today but basically you can go through a
...sequence with the hosts...paradigm buys so you can imagine hollow
...or a phone or tablet or something that you want to enable impair with your developer
machine and xbox and just basically be able to deploy with a to without having
to terror tether to your machine maybe you have four or five phones and,
you just basically want to deploy your application to those different phones and see how they run
on each one is interesting one of the features that actually has
...enumerates phones on the subnet your on...interesting at work you run that
thing...going to be sit there for a while it just keeps going and going and going and but,
when you're tethered to the device it's
basically the local ip make sure that this guy is on?
So, I'm...to go and deploy it.
I'm I thought I might have let me tether and teller roots.
Okay, so, it's deploying into the device.
One thing...
might notice even though I had a csharp application the deployed the dot net framework so,
every application now not just native and
...js they all have a framework packets now which is good
because you get space savings on a low-end device so this guy should deploy.
Okay, so, it succeeded so you can imagine an environment you might actually have assigned
ip addresses to a couple devices and you could if I have a build lab environment where you
configure devices and you say a part of my nightly...I'm just going to just go through and deploy
...app to it and this allows me in the morning just grab the devices
run through some scenarios are run, you know,
coded ui test on it actually see how the app is doing.
So, my app is there.
It's basically the same...
But, I have on desktop.
Running on this device compile for our.
Actually I can touch the screen and this is the same app here running on desktop.
So, this quite a bit difference from what we actually have last time around is that we always had this
...packages regardless if you're going to do a bundle
or not is actually the binary inside the package were not
they were close to being the binary if you were actually compiled...quite a bit of this code
...these are actual the same...across device categories course are always applicable
to architecturally you're running but,
that's basically the demo of actually how you side load now says folks think
that's an improvement...device from...actually had to do before
...see some nodding heads out there.
So, I'm going to switch back to the...and I think jason's up on storage
improvements thanks berkeley.
As long as good talk so one of the things that we heard a lot throughout the from the key
nodes and all throughout the day yesterday and today is that windows ten is targeting
devices that are basically anywhere ranging from like the most powerful to the smallest
and that includes devices that have extremely low storage so one
of the things that we thought about for windows ten is the kind of along the lines of the...saving improvements that
we've...done for universal windows apps these...we really want to make it possible on these
...storage devices to have a first-class experience and.
...has like that we see a lot of these types of devices that are like I have a delve anyway
pro over here it's a great device and,
with these types of devices that are thirty-two or sixteen gig storage install windows in a
lot of some pictures your documents...files you care about by the time, you know,
I'd like you have no more room for apps and you're...I have to go nappy
...stuff I have to move things around yada shuffle you gotta do whatever you gotta do...to be able to install your apps
and that's kind of frustrating so kind of on the theme of storage improvements we
have a feature that we originally introducing windows...one that we're bringing to
finally to desktop here for windows ten and that's being able to install
your universal windows apps to external media and
...is a really cool feature I'm very proud of it I'm really,
really excited that we were able to get everything kind of
slightly working for the demo here today unfortunately to build
...caveat to a...said the bill that you guys have that that's going to be released supports
some scenarios I would go and our try it but we should expect that there are a few bugs here
and there and that there's some rough edges that we're still working through so there's really two things that we've done
it sorry for this category storage improvements the first one is this kind of apps
on external media and the big question that we immediately get as well I'm a
developer and does that mean users can, you know, pull out as...cards or usb drives and they...a
...some other computer and look at the information on those files the
answers no so for external media we went ahead...really make sure that the of the data
there's encrypted the app data and the app payload is encrypted
so tampering becomes a little bit more difficult and...files...
then worse-case app crashes when it runs but there's no integrity...or there's no kind of
data or...after anything like that and that's actually pretty cool and I'm going-to go ahead and demo that a
little bit later the next storage improvements enhancement that we've created
is this shared publisher application data kind of cash so I use the word
cash there because it's something that we expect all developers that have
multiple apps to use and it's something it's...data store that...can be
shared across apps that are within the same publisher so the canonical example
we have a say you have an application...requires some type of authentication and you download
say user profiler some credentials or some something that you want to share...your
apps the good news is now you only need to do that operation one-time any other application that gets
...by your publisher has access to that data previously you're
able to do the same thing, you know, by the internet you could just
send information up and then that information can come down to the other app restored on your
back-end etc here we just made it easier to do and I'm going to
actually do a code demo and, a little bit here as soon as we get
through the apps and other media demo so without further ado didn't want to go ahead and demo
on my device now again caveat is that this device is
a it's a very close...but it's not we were able to get everything working on the official
build so we have and...if you can switch to that guy?
You guys can...see the device here so very familiar what you're going to
do is to start off with is that we have this we introduce this new cp
own settings called storage and this is from the following anyone of these windows phone
...a looks very familiar with us on the colosseum okay
thank?
...better they're that's good...so like very
similar to windows phone you have how much spaces available on each drive I have
...card here that's a sixteen gig as the card and,
just like you would be able to on phone you can set the install to location
from this pc or a different volume now as you'd expect if you have
multiple, you know, drives plugged in each one would be available free install
...on now the key thing here is that very similar to phone is that drive can only be
...to a single device meaning if you have,
for example, to windows ten devices that you want install apps to external media
this device can only be...two-one you can't move it between all the other
devices and kind of going back to the encryption story the data and the apps that
encrypted the encryption is done it up hardware...device and
app level so what that means is apps can't look at each other's data and then the
devices can't look at each other's data so this way we keep the applications that we're intended for
particular device for that device itself so we've already got the apps
stored
here so what I'm going to do is I'm actually going to go to the store I have this app it's called
dickie oats a speech kind of analysis up by microsoft and I'm basically going to
...now that I'm the wife has been orbits body so I'm just...kind of kick it off
...I'm going to let it go now the way that you can see kind of what apps our on your devices
by going kind of digging a step further into the cl and you have this although
it's not really clear here you have this check box and you can choose which one you want
so for now let's go ahead and I've already got some maps kind of preloaded on the device?
We go so I have link I
had this windows phone up and I have my own plug it's called gizmo so what I'm going to do is
we have options from here where if you click on one you can tap you can move it or you can on
...so, that's available for all these apps one
quick node is we similar to windows phone pre installed apps or that
provisions apps the things that come with the device such as, for example, mail-order
calendar ...any like the weather or anything like that those apps
are not able to move we've done that because we want to preserve the experience of the device in case that
st card becomes ejected...make sure that other users if they
...they log into the device still get that first-class experience...have to go and read download all those apps again.
So, the app just popped up down there that's cool
so let's go ahead and actually launch one of these apps.
Magnitude.
Common virgo.
You're holding your own I know.
Here is the windows phone app actually only launch this one two.
And, this is a fat thirty-two
based sd card that running on and everything is encrypted.
And, then I will watch...so that link although I haven't signed any...having problems signing
in so we have all the apps here everything's running all these apps they everything works fine and,
then the next the next question is ok well now I want to move stuff back and forth so again to do
that's very simple you just simply tap
...move you choose your target again if you had multiple
a external drives our external volumes...able to select when you want to move to
...go ahead and move and this will go ahead and start to move operation and basically soon as this
move operation completes so,
the...got killed there which is what I expected and once
the move operation completes at a vanish and then you'll be able to access that
up again from the cl but on the pc side so it'll be
in here somewhere soon as...maybe doesn't refresh others.
So, that's that demo and again the we've done a lot of work to get this working on the
build as far as today and although the option is available we encourage everyone to go out
use it and please let us know how you like it there are some bugs like I've said before I've seen
some myself so we hope that everyone's able to kind of enjoy that feature so,
the next...that actually wanted to go through.
The clicker here is the.
Shared publisher application data and this is kind of...cash and that's a very
...pictures so let's go ahead.
And, I'm number seven I think.
Now that's like a number three.
So, can everyone...my screen great?
What I've got here is basically just a blank application I haven't
had anything to it I simply just credit because visual studios...slow on my machine so,
what I'm going to do is I'm going to show you what we're going to
end up with is that I have this app and basically all this up does
...it goes and it can save it can...can clear the files that are in the
...and I basically have a...here I can type whatever I wanted and then I can save
that data and then I can loaded subsequently from any other application so we're going-to go ahead and build that
...I've done a little bit of the work had a time just snippets
...save time because...watch me code up here onstage the very first thing that we all need
to do is basically to add the declaration to the manifests again we go back to this
manifest the way that we declare we want to use this publisher
cash folder is by adding a new extension of category windows dot publisher
cash folders so in this in this extension declaration you can
basically specify how many folders you...specify the name of those folders so here I've specify the
name is my shared folder and we're going to have to remember this for later because we're actually going to use this
encode?
The second thing that we're going to do is an example I actually just kind of pri cooked all
...animal and really all this has is very similar to this applications
...got the three buttons and then the text box that I can write into and now this is where everything
it's interesting so I have.
First thing I'm going to do is since we're going to be dealing a lot with storage we need to use the.
Storage name space.
And, then I've got the.
Whoops.
I've got the code set up just like all the blank.
Headers for the buttons created.
So, we have the three the three operations the save data
...data and the clear files functions so I'm going to go and implement
those right now so the first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to go and basically store
...folder...get a storage folder I'm just going to call this shared folder.
And, I'm going to basically go from the application data.
Object get the current.
And, then publisher folder and basically already have the shared folder names so I'm just going to use that guy.
The next segmented is going to create a storage file.
I'm going to...shared file onto
And, then I'm going to say shared folder whoops.
Creative file.
And, I'm going to give it a name which is shared filename.
And, then I'm going to say.
And, I'm going to just.
Open coexists I've had some bugs where.
I'm not able to like search crashing.
Right so let's awaits and...say.
...save you guys.
From my core coding skills.
This is what it looks like so basically I create...the storage folder
a grab the shared folder name I...file and then...basically just write the file information
...that file from whatever's in a text box very similarly I would
do the same thing for the load folderor the low data...basically I
read-out from the cache folder and let me actually make sure that you guys can see this.
And, again, it's very similar but the one thing to notice that this is a
cache again so the plan was and I I'm not
sure where it's implemented yet in the cp on a storage sensors are in the setting
...that we want to give users the ability to basically clean-up this
data whenever possible so at any point the data could become deleted
so we encourage you if you plan on using this just know that could be removed at any time and
the last one is about clearing the files so here basically all we're doing is
we're invoking dysfunction that does all the hard work for us and
there's basically just clears all the information in that cash
...setting that text box to empty so let's run this.
And, I've got this guy open so put this over here.
And, it's going it's going.
And, there goes.
as you'd expect I'd be able to type in actually let me just make sure that there's nothing there...because I've been testing
...today so I'll type and here is my test message.
And, then I'll say it's for twenty-four p and I can say that and from here I should be able to
And, then I can say here is an update to this message.
...say this again and then I can loaded again from here
so this is a very simple example but it's just an illustration of kind
of the idea that you can from with separate apps you can actually have this common folder
you can share information...so again as opposed to going up to the web and having to do
all this http requesting and saving things to your back
...have any query down from the other app we've given you a way to do that locally and that's kind of
actually pretty cool so I think we can go back to the slide deck.
And, with that...handed back off to barclay
...continued support all right so we're on home stretch this couple more things
that cover here like I talked about before all previous package versions
are still supported so all they...you have in-store there are no breaking changes
...that term we still support those packages in the store for all
when ten family devices and,
thanks continues to be...path forward I don't know if everybody caught the session I think there
there's a session from a...from my team they're talking about
...store when thirty-two story renown that that's how it's going to use
...packaging as well to be able to install desktop and
dot net when thirty-two applications from the store that is are investment path forward
and, provides us a lot of the benefits that you've learned about today this is
...I chart I was choose to show this because we cover a lot information is around
...what version I pick of the packaging technology what do I get
...to focus really on the right-hand column so with
...the app hacks version ten you get
this new device family targeting capability that we covered earlier that
...available before that's going to allow you to take advantage of features much more
quickly as we ship them encryption epics packages are still not encrypted only
zap packages on mobile are encrypted and haven't been able to pull that one
off...adtext bundles that specific to the app
...technology so-if you want actually bundle apps and only
at have resources that are applicable to the device
pulled down from the store that's really tied to the...packaging technology debug package
...for on this out here all packages or...
sign there's a difference back on mobile and...point one is that
local...packages aren't sign but now all packages or sign taxi...of
assert the identity of where that package actually comes from and,
the differential download update...you actually saw that jason walk
...through that's also only you only get that
and app acts as really enabled through lots of plumbing that's in the os
and up through the store actually how that actually all comes together but it's heavily rely on the package
format as well file single instance thing that's across all windows
ten device families now and it's applicable when you're using...package
...external volume asti is an eight-point one mobile we had this we introduce on a
point one mobile once have gotten quite a bit...usage you can imagine
we've shipped a lot of devices actually have constrain storage so we actually
...at taken this to desktop now not necessarily for desktop like these laptops for demo
going on but this...new pro we're seeing devices go in the market
that you can't solve very many app so this is really expand the storage on that and
the shared publisher storage that's new four-ten ...as chasing kind
of walks through...huge benefit that's a very highly requested
feature over the years were finally able to pull that off we have what we
...alias...email address this ask
app access at microsoft-dot-com that actually comes to me and my family my crew?
Other...you guys almost feel like family in a bad way.
We're running tight on time we're probably going to have a whole lot of time for questions but we will be over
...the expert zone right after this or you can stop by and
ask us questions and here go into the insiders, yeah, so, I'll be in the entire landers that
I think across the street from the windows...you guys come see me okay,
so, some relays session I'm going to walk you through all of these but if you're
interested in actually how this actually works and...actually pulled together
and number related sessions you should go check out some of them are of actually...occured so
you'll have to watch the recorded once couple of more that are going to happen tonight is that the
divx on publishing universal windows apps that's actually tonight john from my
team he's actually covering all the enterprise goodness around deployment and that's next
week at ignite...chicago go check it out if not what it online.
And, again, please fill out a feedback let us know what
...lack which he didn't like what you really wish we...covered but didn't ...thanks-again
for showing up thanks guys thank you moi.